Are you a dog person?
你是爱狗人士吗？
Maybe you have one at home and enjoy taking it for walks and curling up with it on the sofa.
也许你家里养了一只狗，并且喜欢带它去散步，还喜欢和它一起在沙发上蜷缩成一团。
Personally, I‘m not that kind of person - for me they‘re aggressive, smelly animals that need constant care and lack the independent nature and intelligence that cats have.
就我个人而言，我不是那样的人——对我来说，它们是有攻击性的、有异味的动物，需要持续的照料，而且缺乏猫所具有的独立个性和智慧。
But given the life-saving skills that some dogs possess, maybe I should give them a second chance.
但是考虑到有些狗所具备的救命技能，也许我应该再给它们一次机会。
To some a perfect pooch might be one that looks cute, is loyal and sits when it‘s told but that’s about it - it‘s just a pet.
对一些人来说，一只完美的小狗可能是那种看起来可爱、忠诚，并且一叫就会坐下的，但也就仅此而已——它只是一只宠物。
But to really be man’s best friend, they need to do something useful.
但要真正成为人类最好的朋友，它们需要做一些有用的事情。
Some breeds that have amazing sense of smell are put to good use as sniffer dogs or detection dogs, and are trained to use their senses to detect substances such as explosives and illegal drugs.
一些嗅觉极其敏锐的犬种被充分利用作为嗅探犬或探测犬，并且经过训练，利用它们的感官来探测爆炸物和非法毒品等物质。
You‘ll often see them at airports or working with police out on the streets.
你经常会在机场或者在街上看到它们和警察一起工作。
Other types of working dogs include guide dogs, hearing dogs and mobility dogs all providing a life-saving service to their owners.
其他类型的工作犬包括导盲犬、助听犬和行动辅助犬，它们都为它们的主人提供救命服务。
Some dogs can alert emergency services when their owner has a seizure.
有些狗在主人癫痫发作时可以向紧急救援部门发出警报。
And there are clever canines that have been trained to provide affection and comfort to people in hospitals, retirement homes or schools and to people with autism.
还有一些聪明的犬类经过训练，能够为医院、养老院、学校里的人以及自闭症患者提供关爱和安慰。
New uses for dogs are being discovered all the time.
狗的新用途一直在被发现。
Dr Claire Guest is CEO of Medical Detection Dogs, she says “although the dog has a fluffy coat and a waggy tail, he is in fact a highly sophisticated bio-sensor.
克莱尔·盖斯特博士是“医疗检测犬”机构的首席执行官，她说：“尽管狗有一身毛茸茸的毛发和一条摇来摇去的尾巴，但它实际上是一种高度复杂精密的生物传感器。
You know, evolution has given him this highly sensitive nose, going down to parts per trillion.”
要知道，进化赋予了它极其灵敏的鼻子，能够嗅出万亿分之一浓度的物质。”
It‘s this incredible ability that has led to the UK’s National Health Service assessing whether dogs can be used to detect early stage prostate cancer - vital for improving survival rates.
正是这种令人难以置信的能力使得英国国家医疗服务体系在评估是否可以利用狗来检测早期前列腺癌——这对于提高存活率至关重要。
The dogs - usually from the gundog breed, such as labradors and springer spaniels - are taught to detect a sample of urine from a patient with prostate cancer.
这些狗——通常来自猎犬品种，比如拉布拉多犬和史宾格犬——被训练来检测前列腺癌患者的尿液样本。
It‘s also managed to train dogs to detect changes in blood glucose levels in people suffering from type 1 diabetes.
人们还成功地训练狗来检测1型糖尿病患者的血糖水平变化。
One patient, who has one of these medical alert assistance dogs, told the BBC that “in the three and a half years we’ve been together, he has alerted and potentially saved my life 3,500 times.
一位拥有这种医疗警报辅助犬的患者告诉英国广播公司：“在我们相处的三年半时间里，它已经发出警报并可能救了我3500次。
And he does it all for a dog biscuit.”
而它做这一切只是为了—块狗饼干。”